globalspec.com 2016-04-15

# Privacy Policy | IHS Engineering360

### Introduction

GlobalSpec (also known as IHS Engineering360) and its family of products are committed to protecting our users' privacy. This privacy policy is designed to inform users of GlobalSpec-brand products about how GlobalSpec gathers and uses anonymous and profile information, and in what circumstances GlobalSpec will disclose such information. GlobalSpec will take reasonable steps to protect user privacy consistent with the guidelines set forth in this policy and with applicable U.S. laws. 

### Key Definitions

In this Privacy Policy, we use the following key definitions. Other terms are defined in the body of the policy. 

"Clickstream Data" mean the information that GlobalSpec collects through cookies, log files, beacons, and clear GIFs. 

"Content Provider" means a third party that owns a white paper, data, or other document and allows GlobalSpec to link to or display its information from/on the GlobalSpec site. 

"User" or "you" means any person viewing any page on the GlobalSpec site. 

"Third Party Content" means the white papers, data, and other documents available through the web site and owned by Content Providers. 

###  This Privacy Policy Does Not Apply to Third Party and Co-Branded Web Sites. 

Some Third Party Content made available through other organizations is maintained on the web site of the Content Provider, and not on the GlobalSpec site. This means that when you click through to that Third Party Content, you will be leaving the GlobalSpec web site. It will be clear to you when this happens, as the look and feel of your web page will change, and the URL will no longer refer to a web site owned and operated by GlobalSpec. This Privacy Policy does not govern the use and disclosure of any information you choose to disclose to the Content Provider on the Content Provider site. 

In addition, the sites you are viewing may be co-branded, meaning that the sites are branded with the logos of both GlobalSpec and a third party ("Co-Branded Sites"). If you register or log in on a Co-Branded Site, you are choosing to disclose information to both GlobalSpec and the third party with whose brand the site is co-branded. This Privacy Policy only governs GlobalSpec's use of your information. The third party's use of that personal information is governed by the partner's privacy policy, and not by this Privacy Policy. 

### What Information Do We Collect?

**Profile Information:** Our primary goal in collecting profile information (which may include your name and/or the following business - and not home or personal - information: title, address, phone number, fax number and email address) is to provide you with the best and most useful content and services, and to offer you opportunities to obtain other products and services from us and our partners, advertisers and participating suppliers. 

We collect profile information when you provide it to us through the following: when you register on our site, subscribe to an (email) e-Newsletter or Product Alert, register for one of our events/webinars, or register to use certain services (like webcasts and white papers) or through surveys. Several of the products and services that we offer on our sites may require registration as a condition of use. 

**Cookies:** When you view the GlobalSpec web site, a small file called a cookie is placed on your hard drive. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. (However, by not accepting cookies, some of our web pages may not display properly or you may not be permitted to access certain information.) If you register with GlobalSpec by providing your name, email address and/or other contact details, GlobalSpec will use cookies to authenticate your identity when you visit the site and to personalize your user experience, such as by displaying your username when you log on. In all cases, GlobalSpec uses cookies to obtain anonymous information such as the number of visits to the site that a certain user has made, the movement of the user through the site, and the searches that the user conducts on the site. 

You can find out more about "cookies" on our cookies reference page. 

**Clear GIFs & Servers:** We use electronic images known as "clear GIFs" - sometimes called "transparent GIFs", "web bugs", "pixel tags" or "beacons" - that allow us to track general user traffic patterns. GlobalSpec also automatically receives and records information from our servers and from your browser, including your IP address, the time, and information about the page you requested (though these automatic updates do not include your name or other profile information). 

**Subscriber Information:** If you subscribe to an e-Newsletter or Product Alert and become a "Subscriber", GlobalSpec collects your email address. 

Event Registration Information: When registering to attend a GlobalSpec event, the registration form requires users to provide information such as name and corporate title, company name, address, telephone and email address. 

**System Information:** GlobalSpec's event application provides a system test that determines whether you can view a webcast for a GlobalSpec event from your computer. This information is used to optimize the viewing experience and to troubleshoot event webcast viewing problems. We do not collect or retain personally identifiable information in conducting these tests. 

### How Do We Use The Information We Collect?

**Profile Information:** GlobalSpec collects profile information supplied by users who register, as described above. That information lets us better tailor our content to user interests and helps our advertisers better understand the audience they are reaching. All of GlobalSpec is free and is supported by paid content and sponsorships from our advertisers. 

**Subscriber Information:** We use Subscriber Information to deliver email newsletters and Product Alerts on topics of interest to Subscribers who have signed up for those services. We may also send general promotional and marketing materials to Subscribers. We use Subscriber Information to understand our customer base and to market our services to our customers. 

**Third Party Personal Information:** We use third party email addresses provided for the "email a friend" feature only for the purpose of sending e-Newsletters, Product Alerts or event invitations to a subscriber-specified third party, and for no other purpose. 

**Sharing Information:** GlobalSpec may share profile information collected as follows: 

  * Except as set forth herein, your contact information (name, phone number, mail and e-mail address, and other profile information) will not be shared with anyone other than GlobalSpec and the suppliers/advertisers whose information you have viewed (including, but not limited to, phone/fax, web site, supplier profile or e-mail; or product information, including, but not limited to, specifications, product announcements or RFQs) via GlobalSpec or its co-branded sites, e-Newsletters, Product Alerts, and GlobalSpec events.
  * We may send general promotional and marketing materials to our users, including marketing research surveys. We also use profile information to understand our customer base and to market our services to our customers.
  * Profile information collected when you register or log in on a co-branded partner site is available only to GlobalSpec. Strategic partners provide some of the services offered on GlobalSpec. Some of these services require additional registration. When this occurs, GlobalSpec will transfer your profile information to the relevant service provider. You will have the ability to accept or decline the transfer of that information.
  * GlobalSpec email communications are only accessible by designated recipients, except that GlobalSpec personnel involved in management and maintenance may have access to email communications.
  * You can modify your user information by visiting <http://www.globalspec.com/myglobalspec>.
  * You may have your personal information removed from the system by contacting [webmaster@globalspec.com](mailto:webmaster@globalspec.com?subject=Remove%20personal%20information).

### What Information Do We Disclose to Third Parties?

**Disclosure of Anonymous, Aggregated Information**

We provide summary reports to our Content Providers, customers and other third party suppliers/advertisers/service providers, based on our analysis of Clickstream Data. The type of information included in a summary report is "3,000 people looked at your information this week, and of those people 60% clicked through to read the full report." This aggregated information is anonymous and does not disclose to the content providers, advertisers, prospective advertisers, and partners any profile information about the individual users who saw or clicked on their reports. 

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

**GlobalSpec Event Registration Information:** When you register to attend a supplier-sponsored GlobalSpec event, your contact information is used to confirm registrations and send product information and promotional material from GlobalSpec and the event sponsors (information may also be used to compile broad demographic information.) GlobalSpec may disclose your event registration information to those suppliers sponsoring the event. GloblalSpec's customer agreement with the Event Sponsor/Exhibitor provides that the Event Sponsor/Exhibitor may use this information in a manner that is common within their industry, for example, to send you product information, to contact you via common methods of communication to assess your interest in its products and services, and to assess your interest in the Event Exhibitor's products and services. You should contact the Event Exhibitor directly if you have any questions about their use of event registration information. 

###  How Can You Opt Out of Use and Disclosure of Your Information? 

GlobalSpec will only use your profile information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy or subsequently authorized by you. If you do not want your information disclosed in this way, you must not register to view supplier content. Users who would rather not provide any of the user data requested by our registration process do not need to register with us. You can still view some of the content and use some of the services offered by our site without registering. During the registration process (for Web site or Events), we also allow users the option to opt-in and/or opt-out of receiving our electronic Newsletters, Product Alerts, event promotional invitations, or emails from third parties. Users who opt-in may also remove themselves from emailing lists at any time through the edit profile pages or by following the instructions at the end of any email received from the GlobalSpec family of products. 

Note: If you choose not to provide certain profile information when registering for a site, certain products or services may not be available to you. 

**GlobalSpec Event Registration Information:** You can opt out of having your event registration information disclosed to Event Sponsors/Exhibitors by not applying to attend a vendor-sponsored GlobalSpec event. GlobalSpec operates on the basis that users can register to attend events in return for having the above information provided to the Event Exhibitors. If you do not want your information disclosed in this way, please do not register to attend a Globalspec event. 

To contact us regarding a privacy issue, please send an e-mail to [webmaster@globalspec.com](mailto:webmaster@globalspec.com?subject=Events%20privacy%20issue). Please be sure to include the site, conference, e-Newsletter, Product Alert or product so that we may better serve you. 

If you do not want your profile information transferred to a supplier or partner, do not register to access the content. 

If you want your profile information deleted from the GlobalSpec database, please contact us at [webmaster@globalspec.com](mailto:webmaster@globalspec.com?subject=Remove%20personal%20information) and we will remove your profile. 

Profile information provided to us by you is, however, subject to disclosure pursuant to any applicable laws. 

**Access and Updating of Information**

The instructions to review, amend, or delete your information may be found in the edit profile area on any of our sites - <http://www.globalspec.com/myglobalspec>. Users may change information at any time and as often as necessary. Users who are experiencing problems with our services or who have questions about how our services work can contact us by sending an email to: [webmaster@globalspec.com](mailto:webmaster@globalspec.com?subject=Question%20about%20profile). 

**General**

**Registration Password:** Your profile information is password-protected to control access to this profile information by third parties. 

We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. GlobalSpec never asks for passwords in unsolicited phone calls or unsolicited emails. Remember to sign out and close your browser window when you have finished. This will prevent others from accessing your profile information, for example, if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place such as a library or Internet cafe. 

**Links:** The GlobalSpec web site contains links to other web sites. GlobalSpec is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those sites. Users should be aware of this when they leave our site and review the privacy statements of each web site they visit that collects information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by this GlobalSpec site. 

**Business Transfers:** We are always seeking to improve our network of web sites and our business. If all or part of GlobalSpec is sold, merged or otherwise transferred to another entity, the profile information and activity data that you have provided to us may be transferred as part of that transaction. 

**Amendments:** GlobalSpec may modify or amend this policy from time to time. 

### Enforcement

If you believe that GlobalSpec has not complied with this Privacy Policy, or if you have any other complaint with regard to collection, use or disclosure of personal information by GlobalSpec, you may send a written notice of complaint to: 

GlobalSpec, Inc.  
30 Tech Valley Dr  
Suite 102  
East Greenbush, NY 12061  
Attention: User Services 

Email: [webmaster@globalspec.com](mailto:webmaster@globalspec.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Complaint)

GlobalSpec will investigate your complaint and respond to you promptly. 

###  GlobalSpec Events Giveaways: 

Additional Giveaway Rules and Disclaimers apply for registrants attending GlobalSpec Events. See Prize Rules.
